

# JOSÉ JANTARADA

\_

GRAPHIC DESIGNER

## **ABOUT ME**

Hi, my name is José. I'm a freelance graphic designer based in Vila Nova de Gaia, Portugal. My work reflects my journeys through the design, advertising, but most of all, life experiences.

I like everything where I can use my creativity to create new things, although I have a main focus on logo design, branding and identity. I'm passionate about typography and I believe in less is more, something you'll find in my portfolio. My designs characterize themselves by simplicity with a quirky twist.

If you have any ideas, projects or opportunities you'd like to discuss, please get in touch.

### **EDUCATION**

### LICENTIATE DEGREE

Communication Design ESAD / Escola Superior de Artes e Design Matosinhos, Portugal www.esad.pt 2006 - 2007

### **BACHELOR'S DEGREE**

Communication Design ESAD / Escola Superior de Artes e Design Matosinhos, Portugal www.esad.pt 2003 - 2006

## HIGHSCHOOL

Interactive Image (MULTIMEDIA)
IAI / Instituto das Artes e da Imagem
Porto, Portugal
www.iai.pt
2000 - 2003

# CURRICULUM VITAE

### **GENERAL INFO**

### NAME

José Jantarada

### NATIONALITY

Portuguese

### LOCATION

Vila Nova de Gaia, Portugal

### **EDUCATION**

Degree in Communication Design

## **CONTACTS**

### **PHONE**

+351 918 558 423

### **EMAIL**

jose.jantarada@gmail.com

### SKYPE

jose.jantarada

#### VIMEO

www.vimeo.com/josejantarada



## **PORTFOLIO**

### WEBSITE

www.josejantarada.site

# ADDITIONAL TRAINNING

# ADVANCED PROFESSIONAL TRAINING COURSE

Motion Graphics (120 HOURS) AdC / Alquimia da Cor Porto, Portugal www.alquimiadacor.pt Feb. 2013 - May 2013

# ADVANCED PROFESSIONAL TRAINING COURSE

Multimedia Producer (200 HOURS) AdC / Alquimia da Cor Porto, Portugal www.alquimiadacor.pt Jan. 2012 - May 2012

### MODULAR TRAINING COURSE

Adobe FLASH (30 HOURS)
CFA'AD / Centro de Formação
Avançada em Artes e Design
Vila Nova de Gaia, Portugal
www.cfa-ad.com
Nov. 2009 - Dec. 2009

### TYPOGRAPHY WORKSHOP

Tipocracia (10 HOURS)
ESAD / Escola Superior de Artes e Design
Matosinhos, Portugal
www.esad.pt
Oct. 2006

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### **FREELANCE**

Graphic Designer Porto, Portugal 2007 - Present

# MURIS / COMMUNICATION GROUP

Graphic Designer Maia, Portugal www.muris.pt Apr. 2012 - Aug. 2013

## **ADEREÇO / BRAND ACTIVATION**

Graphic Designer Porto, Portugal www.adereco.com Oct. 2008 - Jan. 2012

# COLUNEX / TAILORED COMFORT

Graphic Designer / Traineeship Paredes, Portugal www.colunex.pt Mar. 2008 - Aug. 2008

### M. SOUTINHO / ARCHITECTS

Graphic Designer
Vila Nova de Gaia, Portugal
www.msoutinhoarquitectos.com
Sep. 2007 - Feb. 2008

# **LANGUAGES**

### **PORTUGUESE**

Native

### **ENGLISH**

Written ★★★☆☆
Spoken ★★★☆☆
Listening ★★★☆☆

### **SPANISH**

Written ★★☆☆☆ Spoken ★★☆☆☆ Listening ★★★★☆

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Photoshop Illustrator \*\*\*\* InDesign ★★★☆☆ Affinity Designer \*\*\*\*\*\* Dreamweaver (HTML/CSS) \*\*\* Animate (FLASH) \*\*\*\* After Effects \*\*\* Premiere **★★★☆☆** Final Cut \*\*\*\*\*\* Google Analytics \*\*\*\* MS Office \*\*\*\*\*\* Windows/Mac

# **CLIENTS**

Sogrape Wines, UDACA Wines, APICCAPS, Portuguese Shoes, IMPETUS, Associação Portuguesa da Cortiça, Auditório Serralves, Lavazza, Panike, Carglass, Ergovisão, Grupótico, Parque Nascente, Fórum Aveiro, Freixial Shopping, Ria Shopping, Ogentaly Seguros, VIRTUALP, iBrandit, Bascol Group, Sodecia Group, Cofanor, Laboratorios LETI, Omega Prisfar, Padimat, Associação Empresarial de Sintra, Mercal Consulting Group, Coren Group, Hotel Tryp Porto, Marina Club Lagos Resort, Angstrom, Associação Comercial do Distrito de Viseu, Eurotox, Valcontrol, Polisport.